原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供学习  禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
翻 译     Dialogue: 0,0:07:25.40,0:07:30.40,Default,NTP,0,0,0,,m 211 -8 b 217 -6 217 -4 217 -2 l 217 24 b 217 26 217 29 211 31 l 31 31 b 26 29 26 26 26 24 l 26 -2 b 26 -4 26 -6 31 -8
原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供学习  禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
翻 译     草草  Kahiko  木浅     Alex
翻 译     小食人魔   Giggles  辰星晓Reginamoon
校 对     木浅  某羽
时间轴    念念 知之 Toozii
后 期     斯人
总 监     木浅
《诉讼双雄》前情提要
Previously on Suits.
塔拉・梅瑟  你愿意嫁给我吗
Tara Messer, will you marry me?
愿意  路易  我愿意
Yes, Louis, I'll marry you.
哈维  我不在乎你挣多少钱
I don't care how much money you make
或者睡过多少女人
or how many you women you sleep with.
你的生活存在问题
You have issues in your life
会导致你难以获得真正的爱情
that are going to keep you from having real relationships.
我们的软件和另一个公司的产品
Benjamin and I have an overlap on our software
存在重合部分
with another company.
他使劲了浑身解数拿到了这个
Louis pulled out every trick in the book to get us this.
-那就把钱收下吧  -我想要的不是钱
- Take the money. - I don't want the money.
-唐娜  -我想要更多
- Donna-- - I want something more.
你说"更多"是什么意思
What do you mean more?
我做了个交易  我们解决矿工的案子
I made a deal that we would handle the miners' case
以换取进入律师协会的机会
in exchange for the chance to be admitted to the Bar.
你在逗我吗  你被解雇了
Are you goddamn kidding me? You're fired.
-别这样  -他撒谎  而且不止一次
- Don't do it. - He lied--not once, not twice--
我不在乎  因为我们需要他
I don't care because we need him.
周一早晨  你最好拿出实际行动
Monday morning, you better start putting your money
再为我们接个能赚五万美元的案子
where your mouth is and find us another $50,000 case.
塔拉给我留了个十五秒的留言
Tara left a 15-second voicemail.
内容不是要跟我说她再也不想见到我了
She's either gonna tell me that she never wants to see me again
就是要和好
or she wants to make up.
那是什么
What's that?
预付你一年工资  欢迎回来
Your first year's salary in advance. Welcome back.
哈维  我已经不知道
Harvey, I'm running out of ways
该怎么告诉你我不想做企业律师了
to tell you I don't want to be a corporate lawyer.
我提出了个交易  为你  也为我
I'm offering you a deal. One for you, one for me.
赞助诊所一年  不够
I don't wanna just fund the clinic for a year.
我要两年的赞助
I want to fund it for two,
我想给诊所什么案子  就给什么案子
and any case I want to bring the clinic onto, I can.
成交
Done.
-还有一件事  -你别想要我的办公室
- And there's one more thing. - You are not getting my office.
我不仅要  还要告诉你为什么该给我
Oh, yes, I am, and I will tell you why.
-为什么  -因为她走了  哈维
- Why? - 'Cause she's gone, Harvey.
是时候由你掌权了
It's time for you to take the reins.
哈维  你来做什么
Harvey. What are you doing here?
没事  我就是开着这车兜兜风
Nothing, I was just driving this baby around
然后想起你家这边车位多
and remembered how much street parking you had.
你是想打动我吗
Is that supposed to impress me?
希望能  我是很受打动的
Well, I hope so. Sure as hell impresses me.
见到你很高兴
Well, it's nice to see you,
但如果你想预约  应该先打电话
but if you wanted an appointment, you should have called.
我不是来预约的
I'm not here for an appointment.
我来约你出去
I'm here to ask you out.
你是认真的
You're serious.
我最近想了很多
I've been doing a lot of thinking lately, and...
-哈维  -求你  让我说完
- Harvey... - Please, let me finish.
我们上次分别之后  情况变了很多
Things have changed since the last time I saw you.
我已经不是之前的我了
I'm not the same man that I was.
我跟家人和解
I made peace with my family;
我以前的同事也回来了
I got my old associate back,
从今早起  我是公司的老板了
and as of this morning, I'm the head of my firm,
当我去想该跟谁分享这一切时
and when I thought of sharing that with someone,
我想到了你
I thought of you.
这些不重要
Well, it doesn't matter,
因为医生跟病人约会
because it's completely unethical for a doctor
完全有违道德
to engage in a relationship with her patient.
隔了足够的时间就无所谓
Not if enough time has passed,
而按心理学协会的规定
and according to the APA,
三周前  间隔的时间就足够了
as of three weeks ago, enough time has passed.
-调查的很细致  -当然
- You did your homework. - Sure did.
所以唯一的问题是
So the only question is:
周四八点  还是周六九点
Thursday at 8:00 or Saturday at 9:00?
就一顿饭  如果你显然认为存在的
One dinner, and if this chemistry you
火花并不存在  那我们友好分别
so clearly think exists doesn't, then we part as friends,
不伤感情
no hard feelings.
如果不成
If it doesn't work out,
没伤害  不犯规
no harm, no foul.
周四
Thursday.
如果车太酷炫了
And if the car's too much,
我还是可以让雷开车的
I can always have Ray drive.
我喜欢这车
I like the car.
你说什么  我没听到
What did you say? I couldn't hear you.
我喜欢你的车
I like the car.
很好  你早到了
Good. You're here early.
我需要你为桑德拉办一起消费者诈骗的听证会
I need you to take poing on a consumer fraud hearing for Sandra.
纳森  我们得谈谈
Nathan, I need to talk to you.
好吧
Okay.
我知道那天晚上我们吵得有点凶
I know things got heated between us the other night,
但就我看来  那都过去了
but as far as I'm concerned, it's water under the bridge,
如果你在想我是不是还生你的气
so if you're wondering if I'm still upset at you--
我没有
I'm not.
这是为了确保你听完我要说的
And this is to make sure you're still not upset with me
能继续保持不生我的气
after you hear what I'm about to say.
我为什么拿着一张五十万美元的支票
Why am I holding a check for $500,000?
因为我决定回皮尔逊-斯佩克特-利特律所
Because I've decided to go back to Pearson Specter Litt,
我向你保证过不会抛下你
and I gave you my word that I wouldn't leave you high and dry.
是这样吗  你改了主意
So let me get this straight: you changed your mind,
现在哈维・斯佩克特要买你回去
and now Harvey Specter is buying you back?
如果哈维能说了算  你一分都别想捞到
If it were up to Harvey, you wouldn't be getting a penny.
这是我坚持的
I insisted on this.
我还坚持从今后  我每隔一个案子
Just like I insisted on every other case I take
就办一个无偿案
from now on being pro bono.
听上去你这么做是为了让自己良心好受
It sounds like you insisted on that to make yourself feel better.
不  纳森  我那么做
No, Nathan, I did that
是因为我喜欢做这样的工作
because I care about doing this kind of work,
如果你接受  我甚至愿意
and if you're okay with it, I'd even like the idea
偶尔跟你们合作一些案子
of us partnering on a case every now and then.
但如果我说我不接受这些呢
But what if I say I'm not okay with any of this?
我知道是你在别人都不愿再给我机会
I know that you were the one that gave me another chance
做律师时  给了我机会
to be a lawyer when no one else would,
但别惩罚诊所
but don't punish the clinic.
这是笔大钱  用这钱  你可以另找人
It's a lot of money. With that, you could replace me
并在很长一段时间里帮助很多人
and help a lot of people for a long time.
-那是给我的吗  -不  其实是给我的
- Is that for me? - No, actually, it's for me.
你今晚比以往晚
You're later than usually this morning.
我等了你好一会儿
I've been waiting for you.
唐娜  那晚的事
Donna, about the other night.
我知道你说想要更多  但先听我...
I know you said you wanted more, but before you say anything--
-我想做合伙人  -合伙人
- I want to be a partner. - Partner?
是的  我知道我想要什么了
Yes. I figured out what I want,
我想做律所的合伙人
and I want to be a partner at this firm.
唐娜  我无意侮辱你
Donna, I don't mean to insult you,
但你都不是律师
but you're not even a lawyer.
很好  因为我成为合伙人跟法律无关
Good, because my being a partner isn't about the law.
而是维持律所的运作
It's about keeping this firm running,
而这本就是我一直在做的
which I've been doing for as long as I can remember.
我知道  但那不代表我能让你...
I know that, but it doesn't mean that I can get you--
我为这里奉献了十多年  哈维
I've given over ten years of my life to this place, Harvey,
仅以你秘书的身份我都维持住了律所
and I've done it all from your desk.
我只求一个决策的位置
All I'm asking is for a seat at the table.
这我得跟路易商量
I'll have to ask Louis about it.
那么你是同意了吗
Does that mean that you're on board?
我不知道  今天迈克第一天回来
I don't know. It's Mike's first day back,
这事不小  不仅如此
it's a big ask, and on top of all of that,
我还决定告诉路易
I've decided to tell Louis
我要作为经营合伙人完全做主
that I'm taking full control as managing partner.
恭喜  哈维  但究竟是哪个
Well, congratulations, Harvey, but which is it?
路易  迈克
Louis? Mike?
"不小的事"  因为我不希望
"Big ask." Because I'd hate to think
我鼓起勇气来这么做
I mustered the courage to do this,
可你一上了电梯  就抛在脑后了
and then once you get on that elevator, it's out of your mind.
我保证  我不会忘记的
I give you my word. I will not forget about it.
好
Okay.
*看到钱  就愿意留下吃饭*
*See the money, wanna stay for your meal*
*给你太太再拿块馅饼*
*Get another piece of pie for your wife*
*所有人都想知道那感觉*
*Everybody wanna know how it feel*
*所有人都想见见那景象*
*Everybody wanna see what it's like*
*豆子馅饼我也愿吃  我不在乎*
*I'll even eat a bean pie, I don't mind*
*我和妹子忙着赚钱*
*Me and Missy is so busy, busy making money*
*好了*
*All right*
*退开点  我要跳舞*
*All step back, I'm 'bout to dance*
诉讼双雄 第七季 第一集
*美钞爵士摇摇摇*
*The greenback boogie*
你是睡在这里了吗
Did you sleep in here?
只是来感受一下我的新办公室
Just getting a feel for my new office.
你觉得这墙上能挂得下自行车架吗
You think a bike rack would fit on this wall?
你敢装自行车架  你的第一个无偿案
You put a bike rack in here, your first pro bono,
就只能在我把车塞进你屁股后  自己去打了
you'll be representing yourself after I shove it up your ass.
听上去很不舒服
Wow. That sounds uncomfortable.
说到无偿案
Now, speaking of pro bonos,
你什么时候能把你家老头子的唱片拿出去
when are you gonna get your old man records out of here
好让我安顿下来开始工作
so I can settle in and get to work?
等我们搞定了尼尔・斯蒂尔曼我就搬
I'll get out of here once we take of Neil Stillman.
尼尔・斯蒂尔曼  迪特尔工业那个
Neil Stillman? Detour Industries?
不  尼尔・斯蒂尔曼  绝地议会那个
No, Neil Stillman, Jedi counsel.
好吧  我问是因为尼尔・斯蒂尔曼是公司客户
Okay, I was asking because Neil Stillman is a corporate client,
不是先给我一个我要的  再一个你要的吗
so what happened to one for me, then one for you?
要我提醒你  在企业法律所
Do I need to remind you that at a corporate law firm,
我们优先接手利润丰厚的案子吗
we do the cases that pay the bills first?
更何况  我还没告诉你最妙的部分
Besides, I haven't even told you the best part yet.
再过两星期你就要离开人世了吗
You only got two weeks to live?
不是  等这个案子结束
No. After we're done with this case,
我把尼尔・斯蒂尔曼给你
I'm giving you Neil Stillman.
哈维  我很感谢你的好意  但说实话
Harvey, I appreciate that, but seriously,
既然案子结束你就要把他给我
if you're just gonna give him to me when we're done,
为何不干脆现在就给我
why don't you give him to me now?
无论发生什么情况  我都能处理好
Whatever it is, I can handle it myself.
-我知道  -那你到底是为什么
- I know that. - Then what's going on?
我们完全没有必要一起办这个案子
It doesn't make sense for us to be working together on this.
行  你想听真话
All right, you want the truth?
杰西卡成为管理合伙人后
When Jessica made managing partner,
我和她就不怎么一起办案子了
she and I never really got to do cases together anymore.
你们之前一起办过案子
You used to work on cases together?
是  当年她和我就是现在的我和你
Yeah. She was me and I was you.
黄金组合
We kicked ass.
是吗  那这黄金组合里你主要负责什么
Right. And what exactly did you contribute to the equation?
引用电影台词吐槽  但这不是重点
Oh, movie quotes, mostly, but that's not the point.
重点是我们在一起工作真的很开心
The point is we had a great time doing it.
-哈维  -迈克  我说真的
- Harvey... - Mike, I'm serious.
杰西卡一晋升  我们的关系就变了
Once Jessica stepped up, our relationship changed.
而如果你早知道会如此
And if you'd known that was gonna happen,
肯定希望当时能再一起办最后一个案子
you would have wanted one last case together.
没错  所以怎么样
Exactly. So what do you say?
一起出去找点乐子  顺便大杀四方
We go out and have some fun and kick some ass?
还是留在这里量你的单车架
Or do you want to stay here measuring for your bike rack?
但我不量就没人量了
It's not gonna measure itself.
好好好  我选办案子
All right, fine. Kick ass.
不过这个案子里  我要当绝地律师
But we do this, I want on that Jedi counsel.
长袍  光之剑  都得有
Robes, light saber, whole deal.
你来了  太好了
Good, you're here.
格雷琴  你来干什么
Gretchen, what are you doing here?
-给你送东西  -什么东西
- I'm here to give you these. - What are those?
北半球前九泥浆温泉度假村
Brochures from the top nine mud resorts
宣传册
in the northern hemisphere,
虽然我是不能理解泡泥浴的意义
though I don't know why a person would do that in the first place.
基本等同于泡在自己的粪便里
It's like sitting in a bathtub of your own poop.
你到底想说什么
What the hell are you talking about?
路易  你需要休息
Louis, you need to take yourself some time off.
你还记得你上次休假是什么时候吗
When's the last time you even had a vacation?
9年前的7月
Nine years ago July.
倒霉旅行社给我卖了份地中海俱乐部的孟加拉套餐
Goddamn travel agent sold me a package to Club Med Bangladesh,
所以  绝不
so, hard pass.
什么样的人会去转孟加拉色情俱乐部
What kind of person goes to a sex club in Bangladesh?
不是那样
It's not like that.
我当时刚看完《贫民窟的百万富翁》
I had just seen "Slumdog Millionaire,"
我是想去找寻芙蕾达・平托
and I was trying to find Freida Pinto.
没记错的话她住在伦敦吧
I believe she considers London her place of habitat.
不  我不是说真-芙蕾达・平托
No, I'm not talking about the real Freida Pinto.
我是说属于我的芙蕾达・平托
I'm talking about my Freida Pinto.
叫芙蕾达・平托的人多了去了好吗
There's many different Freida Pintos out there, okay?
所以  我不是白痴  别来烦我
So just--I'm not an idiot. Leave me alone.
路易  我是担心你再这样无所事事郁闷下去
Louis, I'm just worried that if you sit around and stew,
会因为这次分手做出出格的事
this breakup's gonna get the best of you.
格雷琴  我真心感谢你的好意
Gretchen, I really appreciate that,
但我不会无所事事的
but I'm not just gonna sit around.
我将会把伤心焚化为滋润助理们的沃土
I'm gonna be pouring my heartbreak into those new associates.
这样真的好吗
Are you sure that's the best idea?
听着
Look...
我不只是失去了塔拉
I didn't just lose Tara.
我还失去了成为爸爸的机会
I lost a chance at being a father.
而我一直将助理们视如己出
And those associates have always been my children to me.
他们是我的孩子
My children.
而且事实是
And the truth is,
他们进公司后我都没怎么管他们
I've been neglecting them ever since they got here,
但这种情况就到今早为止了
but that ends this morning.
路易  我为你骄傲
I'm proud of you, Louis.
谢谢你  格雷琴
Thank you, Gretchen.
你跑哪儿去了
Where the hell have you been?
尼尔  你一小时前给我打的电话
Neil, you called an hour ago.
也就意味着你应该在半小时内赶到
Well, that means you should have been here in 30 minutes.
可能你不知道  我不是超时免费的披萨快递
Well, I got news for you: I'm not Dominos.
真不幸  因为如果你继续掉链子
That's too bad, because slinging pizzas
做披萨饼搞不好
might be the only job you can get
就是你唯一能做的工作了
if you don't stop shitting the bed.
掉链子  怎么讲
Shitting the bed? How's that?
这两个周我一直在给你打电话
I've been trying to get you on the phone for two weeks.
杰西卡走了  突然之间
Jessica leaves, and all of a sudden,
我就没人管了吗
I start falling through the cracks?
不会没人管  现在我来了
You're not falling through anything. I'm here now,
而且我还带来了最好的初级合伙人
and I brought the best junior partner in the firm.
他就是最好的初级勤杂工也无所谓
I don't give a shit if he's the best junior towel boy.
我有工作交给你  而且十分紧急
I got something for you to do, and I want it done yesterday.
我猜你是想卖掉伏特加酒厂的业务
Let me guess, you want to sell your vodka business.
你怎么知道的
How the hell could you know that?
因为如果你不打算把它卖掉
Because you don't clean up the balance sheet
就不会想要在公司重组半年之后
of your third largest division six months after you restructure
动第三大部门的资产负债表
if you're not looking to put it on the market.
好  我承认你带的人不错
Okay, you brought the right guy.
我想知道的是  你动作怎么这么慢
My question is, what took so long?
我想知道的是  那么着急干什么
And my question is what's the rush?
"因为如果不是为势所迫
'Cause you also don't ram a transaction through
你根本就不必急于脱手
if you don't have to.
我有并购另一个公司的机会
I have an opportunity to buy another company,
-我不想让机会流失掉  -什么公司
- and I don't wanna let it slip away. - What company?
-我可以帮你做尽职调查  -俄罗斯的
- I'll start vetting them for you. - They're Russian,
他们家的业务叫
and they make a little product
不关你事
called none of your goddamn business.
尼尔  为什么这么藏着掖着
Neil, what's with the secrecy?
我们是你的律师
We're your lawyers.
我们需要知道你的打算
We need to know what you're looking to do.
藏着掖着是以防着两周后
The secrecy is in case you're not my lawyers
你们不再是我的律师
two weeks from now.
我不想你们知道我要并购哪家
I don't want you knowing who I'm going after.
你在威胁我们吗
Is that a threat?
这只是确保
It's just my way of making sure
你们不会再甩手不管我的手段
I don't keep falling through the cracks.
现在我们来谈谈条款吧
Now let's talk terms.
早上好  格雷琴  你见到路易了吗
Good morning, Gretchen. Have you seen Louis?
昨晚的事之后  我有点担心他
I'm worried about how he's doing after last night.
我估计他是在拿他的小鸟雏们弥补空虚
My guess is he's in the bullpen with his hatchlings.
他的小鸟雏们
His hatchlings?
我和你一样担心此事
I was concerned about him as you were,
所以之前我打算逼他休假
so I tried to get him to take a vacation.
结果他说他更想好好培养助理
He said he'd rather focus on raising those associates.
好好培养还是好好出气
Focus on them or take it out on them?
就我对他的了解  一半一半
Knowing him, probably 50/50,
但是他拒绝了去世界
but the man turned down a trip
最好的泥浆温泉度假村的机会
to the finest mud resorts in the world,
所以我姑且相信他好的可能更大
so I decided to give him the benefit of the doubt.
那我也相信他吧
Then I will too.
早安  孩子们
Good morning, boys and girls.
谁准备好干掉沃森工业了
Who's ready to tear Watson Industries a new asshole?
这才是好样的  现在在你们的桌子上
That's what I like to see. Now, on your desks,
每个人都发了一份我写的简报初稿
I've made each of you a copy of my initial brief.
要掌握到如数家珍的地步
Cling to it as if you wrote it yourself,
如果有人需要去卫生间
and if any of you need to go to the bathroom,
我建议现在赶紧去  因为接下来两周
I suggest you do it now, because for the next two weeks,
我们都要在这间屋子里过
we are not leaving this room.
谁也不许大便  小便都不行
No one will be shitting. No one will be pissing.
-谁也...  -问吧  问他
- No-- - Go ahead, ask him.
问我什么
Ask me what?
我听说了你的事迹 但是
I heard about your reputation, but...
但是什么
But what?
不用担心我的事迹  孩子
Don't you worry about my reputation, son.
我已经不再是过去的路易了
I am not the same Louis I used to be.
我也许还是很严格  但我也通情达理
I still may be tough, but I have a soft spot,
你有什么需要
so what do you need?
两天假
Two days off.
没问题
No problem.
周六周日你可以休息
Feel free to take Saturday and Sunday off.
他是说周末之外还需要请假
He meant in addition to the weekend.
之外  布莱恩  是这样吗
In addition? Brian, is this true?
-是的  -那么
- Yes. - Then...
周日和周一允许你休假
Monday and Sunday you shall have.
好吧好吧  周一周二
Okay, fine. Monday and Tuesday it is.
-谢谢  利特先生  -不不不  叫路易
- Thank you, Mr. Litt. - No, no, just call me Louis.
介意我问问请假原因吗
Mind if I ask what the occasion is?
-我要当父亲了  -什么
- I'm gonna be a father. - What?
我们要有儿子了
We're gonna have a baby boy.
一个大家都知道你是不可能有的东西
Something everybody here knows is never gonna happen to you.
要当父亲了
Gonna be a father
当一辈子哦
for the rest of his life.
-你说什么  -我说剖腹产
- What'd you just say to me? - I said it's a C-section,
因为孩子有点移位
'cause the baby's actually sideways,
所以我们要...
which means we have to go in there...
你这个目中无人的混蛋
You self-centered piece of shit.
你以为我是真的想知道吗
Do you think I care about the graphic details?
-我只是以为...  -以为什么
- I just thought-- - Thought what?
以为你根本不在乎自己的工作吗
That you don't give a shit about your job?
我告诉你  你人在这里  就得工作
Let me tell you something: when you work here, you work here.
不允许想家想亲人想孩子
You don't think about home and families and babies.
所以下次你要把你的私人生活
So the next time you want to put your personal life
置于公司需求之上时
ahead of the needs of this firm,
最好提前一年跟我请假
you better goddamn come to me a year in advance.
这不公平
That's not fair.
他不可能提前一年知道要生孩子...
He couldn't have known he was gonna have a baby a year--
我告诉你  斯蒂芬妮
Let me tell you something, Stephanie:
也许是你不清楚生孩子的事
maybe you don't know how babies are made,
因为想要孩子的人  就知道自己在尝试
because when people are trying, they know they're trying,
就因为没人愿意和你尝试
and just because no one ever wants to try with you
不代表你就有权
doesn't give you the right
教我怎么管理助理
to tell me how to run my associates.
听懂了吗
You got that?
懂了
Got it.
你在想我在想的吗
You thinking what I'm thinking?
不一定  你在想什么
Depends. What are you thinking?
我在想我们有加伏特加酒厂要卖了
I'm thinking we've got a vodka company to sell.
你还说过你想找点乐子
You already said you wanted to have some fun.
没错  二者相加
That's right, and you put those two together,
结论是什么
what have we got?
派对
Party.
看  我们达成一致了
See? We're already on the same page.
不如你去找个好地方
Why don't you get a kick-ass location,
-我负责找模特  -模特
- and I'll get the models. - Models?
我喜欢模特  为什么不能让我找模特
I like models. Why can't I get the models?
有道理
You make a good point.
这活需要两个人  我们一起找吧
It's a two-man job. We'll both get the models.
哈维  说真的  这个派对
Harvey, seriously, why do we even have to
为什么需要模特
have models at this party?
两个原因  其一  大家想看模特
Well, two reasons. First, people expect it,
总要满足大家的需求
and you've got to give the people what they want.
没错  其二
Right, and second,
到场的凡是整晚调戏模特的人
any dipshit who shows up and hits on the models all night
都不是诚意买家
isn't a serious bidder for the company.
看来你确实有资格入住我办公室了
Huh, you really are ready for my office.
说到你办公室
Hey, speaking of which,
你到底什么时候让出来
when exactly is that gonna happen.
现在没空说这个
I can't talk about that right now.
我忙着去调戏模特呢
I got to go hit on some models.
哈维  撇开玩笑话
Hey, Harvey,jokes aside,
之前你说
what you said before about
希望我们像以前一样一起办案
us working together like the old days,
我很感激
I appreciate it.
对我意义重大
It means a lot to me.
我也是
Me too.
-没种  -没种
- Pussy. - Pussy.
唐娜  有时间吗  我需要你帮忙
Donna, do you have a minute? I need your help.
没问题  怎么了
Of course. What's going on?
路易已经失控了
Louis is out of control.
是艾斯特婚姻问题那种失控
When Esther got married out of control,
还是哈维当上高级合伙人那种
or when Harvey made senior partner out of control?
还要糟
Worse.
那糟了  他做了什么
Shit. What did he do?
冲助理们发火去了
He just went off on the associates.
异常狂暴  残忍而且可怕
He was abusive and cruel and ugly.
唐娜  我从来没见过这样的路易
Donna, I have never seen Louis like this before.
瑞秋  如果真如你所说
Rachel, if what you're saying is true,
那我们就需要弄清楚原因
then we need to figure out why,
因为路易这样从来都是为某件事...
because with Louis, there's always a reason--
塔拉昨晚和他分手了
Tara broke up with him last night.
-天哪  -他得知消息时我就在场
- Oh, my God. - I was there when it happened.
这不是什么他能很快放下的事
This is not something that he's going to get over quickly.
-你什么意见  -我建议
- So what are you saying? - I'm saying that
应该由我接管助理
I think I should take over the associates
直到他能控制好自己的情绪
until he's able to get his emotions under control.
瑞秋  夺走他的助理
Rachel, taking the associates away
可不是能稳定他的办法
isn't exactly gonna stabilize him.
这是他仅剩的了
That's the one thing he has.
我知道  但我必须说
Yeah, I know that, but I'm telling you,
如果处理不好  肯定会有人报复他
if we're not careful, someone's gonna do something to him,
到时候只是被告都得算他幸运了
and he'll be lucky if it's just suing him.
这话你跟他说了吗
Did you tell him that?
我去找他了  刚进他办公室
I tried to, and he bit my head off
就被他一通痛骂  所以...
the minute I walked into his office, so...
好  我去找他谈
Okay, I'll talk to him.
但你得先把事情原原本本告诉我
But I'm gonna need you to tell me exactly what he did first.
不管什么事我现在都没空  唐娜
Whatever it is, I don't have time, Donna.
据我所知  你今早倒是有空
From what I heard, you had time
去跟助理们发火呢
to go off on the associates this morning.
谁跟你说的  胡扯
Who told you that? That's bullshit.
你是说你没有冲布莱恩・阿特曼发火
Are you telling me you didn't go off on Brian Altman
然后又对斯蒂芬妮・帕特尔的
and then make a horrible comment
性生活进行了言辞激烈的评论吗
about Stephanie Patel's sex life?
这叫管教  唐娜
It's called discipline, Donna.
这叫可诉  路易
It's called actionable, Louis.
你现在没有已经被告
You're lucky that there isn't a lawsuit
已经是幸运了
on your desk right now.
谢谢你的忠告
Well, thank you for your counsel.
我知道我在做什么
I know what I'm doing.
路易  我在努力体谅你
Louis, I am trying to be understanding,
但我觉得
but I think Rachel should
应该让瑞秋来负责助理们
handle the associates for right now.
-你在开玩笑吗  -不  我没有
- Is that a joke? - No, it's not.
那我来解释下
Well, then let me explain
什么叫所谓的地位
a little something to you called pecking order.
我在这里  瑞秋在这里
See, I am up here. Rachel's down here.
你不能让处于这种低位置的人
And you don't give dominion over your associates
来管理助理
to someone down here.
我知道  但我还知道
I know that, but I also know that
塔拉昨晚和你分手了
Tara broke up with you last night,
所以你现在不在状态
and you're not in your right mind.
我不想再听到这个名字了
I don't want to hear that name again.
路易  我想说的是如果你解决此事
Louis, all I'm saying is if you don't deal with it,
你会一直虐待助理们
you're gonna keep abusing the associates,
-他们将会...  -唐娜  我告诉你
- and then we're gonna have-- - Hey, Donna, you know what,
我本来不想这么做
I didn't want to do this,
但刚才我没有提这件事
but I did leave one name off the chart.
我  瑞秋  你
Me. Rachel. You.
所以你也没资格告诉我我该怎么做
So don't you tell me what to do.
路易  我就不揪着你这句话了
Louis, I'm gonna let that go,
因为我知道你现在很受伤
because I know you're hurting,
但是恰恰证明我说的是对的
but that right there is exactly why I'm right,
因为如果你跟我都这么说话
because if you're willing to talk to me like that,
那你对助理们的态度真的要惨不忍睹了
God help those associates.
-喂  -是感觉良好医生吗
- Hello? - Yes, is this Dr. Feelgood?
我想预约一次谈话
'Cause I'd like to schedule an appointment
越快越好
as soon as possible.
抱歉  你打错电话了
I'm sorry. You've got the wrong number.
我是我有正事要做医生
This is Dr. I Have Work to Do.
既然这样  我想预约一次谈话
Well, in that case, I'd like to schedule an appointment
越快越好
as soon as possible.
哈维  你到底为什么给我打电话
Harvey, why exactly are you calling me?
首先  先回答我
First, answer me this:
自从你答应我之后
how many times have you considered
几次想要拿起电话
picking up the phone and telling me that
告诉我你后悔了
you've reconsidered since you said yes?
四次  如果不算现在这次的话
Four. If you don't count right now.
这么说吧  我打给你的原因是
Then let's just say I'm calling to tell you
我刚刚和一屋子模特待了一个小时
that I've been in a room full of models for the last hour,
然而我脑海里想的都是你
and all I can think of is you.
还在考虑拒绝我吗
Still thinking of cancelling on me?
不  哈维
No, Harvey.
我也期待我们的晚餐
I'm looking forward to our dinner as well.
你是不是把我们的婚礼日子提前了
Did you move up the date of our wedding
还忘了告诉我
and forget to tell me?
不是  我打扮成这样是因为
No, I got to get dressed up for this thing
我和哈维要去见个客户
that Harvey and I are going to for a client.
为了一位客户打扮
A thing for a client.
说的一点都不特别
That's not very specific.
我的意思是  这事不好解释
Uh, yeah, I mean, it's just kind of hard to explain.
这事是不是和三十六名模特
Hmm, does it involve three dozen models
加一堆伏特加有关
and 1,000 bottles of vodka?
看来也不没那么难解释
I guess it's not that hard to explain.
你打算什么时候告诉我
When were you gonna tell me?
如果不是提前说  那肯定是之后说
If not before, then definitely after...
或者根本不说  不太好说
or never. It's hard to tell.
我还没认真想过
I haven't really thought this through.
-你知道我在开玩笑  对吧  -是的
- You know I'm kidding, right? - Yes.
-你也应该来  -我去不了
- You should come. - I can't.
我和卡特里娜忙着帮齐本德尔剧团上市
Katrina and I are taking the Chippendales public,
我们要去见几位他们那里的首席舞者
so we're gonna meet with a few of their top dancers
做一些文书工作  估计要忙一晚上
to go over some paperwork. Probably take all night.
-一点意思都没有  -是的  没有
- So that's not funny. - Yes, it is.
我认真的  瑞秋  你应该一起去
I'm serious, Rachel, you should come.
哈维好像搞了一架直升机
I think Harvey got a helicopter.
我们可以坐直升机环绕城市
We should take a ride around the city.
我去不了  你去吧
I can't. You go.
说来话长  短版本就是...
It's a long story. I ju--
我可能要接管所有助理
I might be taking over the associates,
果真能如此  我希望提前做好准备
and if I do, I just want to be prepared.
太棒了  瑞秋  但你这是说
Rachel, that's amazing, but are you telling me
路易真的愿意放手吗
that Louis is really ready to give that up?
那个就是长版本
That's the long story.
但是我晚一点会告诉你的
But I'll tell you about it later tonight.
-我可以留下  -不  你应该去...
- I can stay. - No, you should go--
太好了
Great, okay.
-我爱你  -我也爱你
- I love you. - I love you too.
唐娜  在你走之前  能和你说几句吗
Donna, before you leave, can I talk to you for a second?
又怎么了
What is it now?
公司的咖啡滤纸不够了吗
We're running low on coffee filters?
找不到糖了吗
Can't find the Sweet 'n Low?
还是路易终于因为太混蛋被告了
Or is Louis finally being sued for being an asshole?
你想告诉我发生了什么
You want to tell me what's going on,
还是你想一直继续
or you want to keep firing your pistol
攻击同盟
in the wrong direction?
抱歉  格蕾琴
I'm sorry, Gretchen.
我真的厌烦了大家总来找我解决问题
I am just sick and tired of being everyone's go-to
但我却得不到我想要的
and not getting what I ask for.
我不想让你觉得我漠不关心
I don't mean to sound insensitive,
但是你是企业秘书
but you're a corporate secretary.
你到底期望些什么
What exactly did you expect?
你真的想知道吗
You really want to know?
我问哈维要了上桌的资格
I asked Harvey for a seat at the table.
-什么桌子  -合伙人的桌子
- What table? - The partnership table.
怪不得他拒绝了你
No wonder he shot you down.
他没有拒绝我
He didn't shoot me down.
他跟我说他要考虑一下
He told me he would think about it,
但还没答复  我都不知道他还会不会答复
but I haven't heard anything, and I don't know now if I will.
有个得到他注意的办法  是去他办公室
One way to get his attention is to go in there
拿起你给他的支票  然后撕掉
and take that check you gave him and rip it the hell up.
-什么支票  -你给他的入股公司
- What check? - The check you gave him
做合伙人的资金
for your partnership money.
-你没给他是吗  -没有
- You didn't give him one, did you? - No.
红毛  我告诉你
Let me tell you something, Red.
你想要上桌儿
You want a seat at the table,
就得下点本儿
you got to put some skin in the game.
终于来了  哈维
There he is. Hey, Harvey,
这是个好主意
This was a great idea, huh?
-很高兴我想出了这个点字  -开心吗
- Glad I thought of it. - Are we having fun?
如果你觉得和一名叫斯维特拉娜的模特
If you call talking geopolitics
聊地缘政治学算开心
with a model named Svetlana fun,
那就没错  非常开心
then that would be a big, fat bowl of yes.
镇定  小老虎  酒保在倒酒了
Easy, tiger. The bartender's pouring doubles.
那你又是来干什么的
And what are you doing here?
我要再来一杯  我是让你小心别醉了
I'm having another drink. I said for you to be careful.
-我不会醉的  -好吧
- I can handle my liquor. - Okay.
我举了几根手指
How many fingers am I holding up?
你看不出来吧
You can't tell, can you?
谁说不会醉来着
Who can't handle my liquor now?
我想让你吃点东西  但不巧的是
I'd tell you to put food in your stomach, but unfortunately,
我只点了些
I only ordered enough
用来装点门面的食物
to give the appearance of having food.
所以总的来说  你只想
So basically, you're just trying to get
把这些家伙灌醉来让你哄抬标价
these guys hammered so you can drive up the bidding.
不  我说过了
No. I told you,
那些调戏模特的家伙都不是认真的
the guys hitting on the models aren't serious.
-现在我告诉你...  -那些想把
- Now I'm telling you... - That the guys
自己灌醉的家伙也不是认真的
who let themselves get drunk aren't serious,
也就是说那些没醉的
which means whoever's left are the bids
才是我们今晚要拿下的投标人
that we have in our hands at the end of the night.
你早就知道了  对吗
You knew it the whole time, didn't you?
不看看和你说话的是谁
Who do you think you're talking to?
好伙计
Good man.
有一个小问题
There's just one small problem.
如果  我一不小心成了那些
What if, by accident, I happen to be one of the people
灌醉自己的家伙怎么办
that let himself get too drunk?
你只管放开了喝
You just might as well keep drinking,
如果我们玩的不尽兴
'cause if we're not having fun,
那何苦待在这里
what the hell are we doing here?
好极了  明白
Yes! Copy that.
斯维特拉娜
Svetlana...
你清楚这间办公室不会自己收拾好的  对吧
You know this office isn't gonna pack itself up, right?
还没收拾是因为我们其中之一
It's not packed because one of us
之前三小时一直在工作
has been at work for the last three hours.
另一个不过是为了昨晚的工作
The other one of us was sleeping off
好好睡了一觉
all the work he did last night.
你是说你伏特加喝的宿醉未醒
You mean you're hung over from all the vodka you drank?
没错  我就是这个意思
Yeah, that's what I just said.
我真不该请你回来
I never should have hired you back.
现在想解雇我已经晚了
Well, it's too late to fire me now.
是吗
Is it?
因为如果你对得起你的薪资
Because if you were worth your salary,
你会问我们找到几个投标人了
you'd ask how many bids we're sitting on.
没必要问  我有脑子
I don't have to ask, because I've got this.
访客名单上有500人
Guest list was 500,
有一半是冲着模特来的
and half of them came for the girls.
剩下的有一半没什么钱
Half of the other half don't have the capital,
其中有百分之六十醒来后
and 60% of the rest of them woke up
觉得他们并不想掺和酒业
realizing they don't want to work in the liquor business.
就算  我不确定
Take, I don't know, what,
最多47个来竞争
47 off the top for good measure?
最后我们能收到的也就三个竞价
Leaves us with three bids.
-唐娜跟你说了  对吗  -可能吧
- Donna told you, didn't she? - Probably.
她有没有让你过来做点什么
Did she bother telling you what we're doing now?
-不用她说  你可是哈维・斯佩克特
- She didn't have to, 'cause you're Harvey Specter.
你也就那一招  几年前已经传授给我了
You've got one trick, and you taught it to me years ago,
我们走吧
so let's go.
你知道我可不只一招  对吧
You know I have more than one trick, right?
不  我知道你以为是这样
No, I know you think you do,
但是新瓶里装的
but just because you put on a different costume
可不一定是新酒
doesn't make it a different trick.
好吧  你还是喝醉时比较讨喜
Yeah, I liked you better when you were drunk.
我喝醉时你也更讨喜
I liked you better when I was drunk too.
我不管他们怎么说  都是胡扯
I don't care what they say. This is bullshit,
我不想被耍的团团转
and I'm not gonna get played.
先生们  不好意思  我第一天上班
Gentlemen, we're so sorry. It's my first day.
很显然  我和哈维同一时间
Evidently, I booked the conference room
-订了这间会议室  -胡说
- at the same time as Harvey. - Bullshit.
你们以为我们不知道你们的打算吗
You think we don't know what's going on here?
你们订一间会议室是想逼我们出更高的价
You double booked the room to scare us into overbidding.
你说得对  我们早该想到
You're right. We should have known
像你们这些精明人士
a couple of smart guys like you
绝不会上这种愚蠢的当
would never fall for the banana in the tailpipe.
我们带你们来这里是因为
We brought you down here just because you were
只有你们两人出价一亿
the only two bidders who came in at 100 million,
所以现在  你们两个好好看看
so now, you have to look each other in the eye
旗鼓相当的对方
while you go head-to-head.
接下来会这样
So here's what's gonna happen:
你们有一次机会写下你们的最高竞价
you got one chance to write down your best bid.
赢家通吃  输家走人
Winner takes all, loser goes home.
我们15分钟后见
We'll be back in 15 minutes,
希望能看到更高的竞价
and we better see some more zeroes.
如果我们串通呢  就在这儿
What if we collude, right here?
你们最多能拿到一亿
Stick at 100 and you're shit out of luck?
顺便一说  这恰恰是
Which, by the way, is exactly why
你们不订一间会议室的原因
you don't double book a conference room.
这里只有一个问题
There's only one problem with that.
当我们说只有你们
When we said you two were
出价一亿时
the only ones that came in at 100,
我们没说没人出更高的价
we didn't say there wasn't someone who put down more.
-阿克谢罗德  -没错
- Axelrod. - Bingo.
二次竞价20分钟前就来了
Second bid came in 20 minutes ago.
所以如果你们想串通的话  请便
So if you two want to collude, go right ahead,
但是你们最好出价远超过一亿
but it better be for a hell of a lot more than 100 million.
-进展如何  -这要看情况了
- How'd it go? - That depends.
-阿克谢罗德二次竞价是多少  -两亿
- What was Axelrod's second bid? - 200 million.
这样的话进展如何都不重要了
Well, then it doesn't really matter how it went,
因为不管这些小丑出价多少
because whatever those clowns come up with,
尼尔・斯蒂尔曼都会抱回大笔现金
Neil Stillman's walking away with a boatload of cash.
说到大笔现金...
Speaking of boatloads of cash...
这是张50万的支票
It's a check for half a million dollars.
我告诉过你我是真的想要
I told you I was serious about
成为合伙人  我也真的是认真的
becoming a partner, and I am.
-唐娜...  -哈维  说实话
- Donna... - Harvey, be honest.
你还没考虑过我们
You haven't given one thought to
昨天讨论过的事
what we talked about yesterday.
我最近有点忙
I've been a little busy.
你总想岔开这个话题
And you've also been avoiding the subject.
这么一来  你就得认真对待了
This way, you have to take me seriously.
我有认真对待此事
I do take you seriously.
那就去路易的办公室
Then walk the hell down to Louis' office
告诉他我要当合伙人
and tell him I'm a partner.
唐娜  我不能把每个决定直接
Donna, I can't just ram every decision
-通知给他  -每个决定
- down his throat. -Every decision?
你到现在还没告诉他你要坐上
You haven't even told him that you're stepping
杰西卡的位置
into Jessica's shoes yet.
我在等合适的时机
I'm waiting for the right time.
如果我是合伙人的话  我会告诉你
And if I were a partner, I would tell you that
-昨天就是绝佳时机  -唐娜...
- the right time was yesterday. - Donna...
哈维  你觉得我在要你可怜我吗  我没有
Harvey, you think I'm asking for charity, I'm not.
我要你为我这些年做过的事
I am asking for you to make official
给我个交代
what I have been doing for years anyway,
也就是给你出谋划策  就像你需要
which is giving you advice, like you need to step
去告诉路易你是这儿的老大
the hell up and tell Louis that you're in charge,
现在  不管你接不接受
and right this second, you're either gonna take that advice,
这个建议  现在你应该
or you're not, but it is time
对我的工作
that you recognize me
予以认可了
for what I do.
我哥哥托马斯比我聪明
My brother Thomas is the clever one.
在剑桥教书
Teaches at Cambridge.
一周工作20小时  暑假休息
20 hours a week, summers off.
你没在听我说话  对吗
You're not listening to a word I'm saying, are you?
-我很抱歉  -你是该道歉
- I'm sorry. - Well, you should be.
大家都说我还挺招人喜欢的
I've been told I'm actually quite delightful.
你确实是  我只是有点分心了
You are. I'm just a little distracted.
开胃菜才吃了一半
Halfway through appetizers.
等到酒浸烧烤端上桌来
Doesn't bode very well for how you'll be feeling
-就不知道你会怎样了  -不是你想的那样
- when our flambé arrives. - It's not that.
杰西卡上个月离开了事务所
Jessica left the firm last month.
大家都认为我是继承人
Everyone assumes that I'm next in line,
而现在唐娜又来告诉我  如果我不快点
and now I've got Donna telling me that if I don't step up...
等等  我以为你有一天早上说过
Wait a second, I thought you told me as of the other morning
你现在已经是公司老大了
that you're now head of the firm.
确实是  只是我还没告诉路易
I am. I just haven't told Louis yet,
而唐娜逼着不放
and Donna won't let it go.
我觉得这次见面就是个错误
I think this may have been a mistake.
-什么  -你不是来和我约会的
- What? - You didn't come to me to date me,
你来找我是因为你正处于另一场危机
you came to me because you're in the middle
而你需要我来帮你度过它
of another crisis and you need me to walk you through it.
才不是这样
That's not true.
你当然不这样想
Of course you don't think it's true.
如果你这样想  你就会给我办公室打电话
If you did, you would have called my office
-来预约治疗了  -我不需要预约
- and made an appointment. - I don't need an appointment.
我是要和你分享生活中的事情
I'm sharing things about my life.
据我所知  人们约会的时候就是这样做的
Last time I checked, that's what people do on dates.
这没错  哈维  但是第一次约会的时候
Yes, it's what they do, Harvey, but on first dates,
人们也会尽力让对方感觉到他们很特别
they also try to make the other person feel special
-而且有人愿意听他们说话  -宝拉
- and listened to. - Paula--
你知道为什么  心理医生与客户约会
Do you know why it's unethical for a therapist
是违反职业道德的吗  哈维
to go out with her client, Harvey?
当然知道了
Yeah, of course I do.
因为客户会自然而然地
It's because it's natural for a client
将不真实的情感和爱意
to transfer feelings of desire
转移到心理医生身上
onto his therapist that aren't real.
-我知道这一点  -但你不知道的是
- I know that. - What you may not know
心理医生有这样的移情
is that it's not unnatural
也是再正常不过的
for a therapist to feel the same way.
你以为我对你就没抱过幻想吗
You don't think I've had fantasies about you?
幻想着有一天  当我晚上准备回家的时候
That one day you'd show up at my office
你会出现在我的办公室
as I was heading home for the night,
我一转头就会看见你
and I turn around, and you'd be there.
你什么都不说
You wouldn't say a word, but...
把我拥入怀中  开始吻我
you'd take me in your arms and kiss me, and...
而那将是一段特别的感情的开端
it would actually be the start of something special.
我有过这些幻想
Well, I have,
所以  虽然我有更好的判断力
which is why despite my better judgment,
我还是来和你约会了
I'm here with you right now.
-所以说问题在哪  -问题是在这些幻想中
- So what's the problem? - The problem is those fantasies
我不应该是你的心理医生
weren't of me being a therapist to a man
而你害怕到不敢承认自己需要帮助
who's still too afraid to admit that he needs help,
更别说是掌控一家以你冠名的事务所了
much less take control of a firm that bears his name.
谢谢你的晚餐  哈维
Thank you for dinner, Harvey.
如果你需要治疗  请给我办公室打电话
If you need a session, call my office.
遗憾的是  我不能再当你的治疗师了
Unfortunately, I can't see you anymore,
但我可以给你推荐一些
but I can give you a recommendation
可能的人选
for someone who can.
-路易  我能做什么  -为我吗
- Louis, what can I do-- - Do for me?
你可以告诉我  今后你对我再有什么不满
You could tell me from now on if you have a problem with me,
你可以和我当面说  别在我背后捣鼓
you'll take it up with me instead of going behind my back.
-什么  -这就对了
- What? - That's right.
你以为我不知道这件事吗
You think I don't know the whole
"瑞秋应该负责我的助理律师"这种狗屁
"Rachel should be in charge of my associates"
是你说的  而不是唐娜
bullshit came from you and not Donna?
没错  是我说的
You're right. It was from me.
我最先来找的你  而你把我凶惨了
And I came to you first, and you bit my head off.
那我就换种
Well, then let me tell you in a way
不会伤害你这小可人的方式来说
that won't harm your pretty little head,
我都忘了你有多娇贵了
because I clearly forgot what a delicate little flower you are.
这些助理都是我的
Those associates are mine,
除非等我死了那天  你来从我手里撬走
and the only way you're ever gonna get them
否则你永远别想拿到
is if you pry them from my cold, dead hands.
唐娜  除非是紧急情况
Donna, unless it's an emergency--
这就是紧急情况
It is an emergency.
我需要知道我的事你办得怎么样了  哈维
Harvey, I need to know what you're doing about me.
唐娜  现在时机不对
Donna, right this second is not the time.
时机正对  要是没人尽快
It is the time, because if somebody doesn't
对路易采取行动
do something about Louis soon,
事务所就要被自己的助理起诉了
this firm is gonna end up being sued by our own associates.
我没有权限做什么
I don't have the authority to do anything,
而你都不知道我说的是怎么回事
and you don't even know what I'm talking about.
好吧  唐娜
Okay, Donna.
你赢了  你是合伙人了
You win. You're a partner.
哈维
Harvey.
我们有麻烦了
We got a problem.
这次又是什么
What is it now?
你看一下
Take a look.
你是从哪儿拿到的
Where'd you get this?
我从哪拿到的不是重点
It doesn't matter where I got it.
重点是文件已经传出来了
It's out there.
你又不能确定尼尔知道
You can't be sure Neil knew this.
这有什么区别吗
What difference does that make?
因为如果他不知道的话
Because if he didn't know,
-就只是倒霉了  -哈维  他可是首席执行官
- it's just bad luck. - Harvey, he's the goddamn CEO.
他知道  他瞒着我们
He knew. He kept it from us,
而且他还瞒着那些收购他公司的人
and he kept it from the guys buying his company.
-这你可不知道  -我知道的
- You don't know that. - Yes, I do.
我也知道你还有时间去阻止
I also know you still have time to go stop
-这次收购  -你是在开玩笑吧
- this sale from going through. - Are you kidding?
文件已经签了  收购已经完成了
They signed the documents. It's already gone through.
款项还没转手
Money hasn't changed hands yet,
所以你还有时间
so you still have time to stop it.
-迈克  -哈维  如果你不过去
- Mike-- - Harvey, if you don't get over there
-在转手之前找到  -好了  我会处理的
- and find out before-- - All right. I'll handle it.
-你要去哪儿  -我要和路易谈谈
- And where are you going? - I need to talk to Louis.
不管是什么事  都要等到明天
Whatever it is, it's gonna have to wait until tomorrow,
因为如果你不在钱款转手前
because if you don't get over there
赶到那里
before that money changes hands,
那就是置我们于各种危险之前了
you are opening us up to a shitload of trouble.
这里晚上有点吓人  是吧
Kind of creepy in here at night, isn't it?
还好吧  我倒觉得挺平静的
Oh, I don't know. I find it kind of peaceful.
那干嘛要卖掉它  而且最重要的
Then why get rid of it? And more importantly,
你为什么想要交易这么快就完成
why'd you need the sale to go through so quickly?
我说过  我有个收购机会
I told you, I have another opportunity.
如果要我说  真正的原因是
And what if I said the real reason was
你知道你的伏特加生意要被起诉了
you knew you vodka business was about to be sued
因为你用了另一个品牌的配方
for using another brand's recipe?
而我会说我不知道这些
I would say I did not know that.
-而你其实知道  -又不能改变什么
- Well, now you do. - It doesn't change a thing.
那两个笨蛋已经签了合同
Those two dipshits already signed the agreement.
尼尔  这看着就像是你要我
Neil, this looks a hell of a lot like you're asking me
-跟你合伙诈骗  -我是要你做好本职工作
- to be a party to fraud. - I'm asking you to do your job.
为我谋取利益  相信我说的话
Look out for my interests, and take me at my word.
如果我有理由相信你在说谎  而我确实相信...
If I have reason to believe that you're lying to me, which I do--
唯一一件你要相信的事是
The only thing you have
如果你不这样做  我就会炒了你
reason to believe is that I will fire you
如果你不答应我  我会另找他人
if you don't do this for me and then find someone who will,
没有你地球照样转
so this thing is gonna get done whether you do it or not.
唯一确定的是如果你不答应
The only thing that happens if you don't
外界会坚定此前的风言风语
is that the world will know what people suspect already:
也就是你无法代替杰西卡
that you can't fill Jessica's shoes.
如此一来你认为多长时间
How long do you think it's gonna take after that
你的每位客户会开始离你而去
before every one of your clients starts to leave you?
所以现在告诉我答案
So you tell me right now,
你加入还是退出
are you in or not?
见鬼  奥利佛
Shit. Oliver.
最近怎样  迈克
What's up, Mike?
-新工作还好吗  -我很抱歉
- How's your new job? - I'm sorry.
我发誓我准备告诉你的
I swear I was gonna tell you.
是啊  我听说了
Yeah, I heard,
但我想你的确往前走了  对吗
but I guess when you move on, you move on, right?
拜托  不是这样的
Come on, it's not like that.
胡扯  不是这样的
Bullshit, it's not like that.
你离开了  迈克  扔下此前一切承诺
You left, Mike, after everything you said.
你能让我解释下吗
Would you please just let me explain?
我曾竭力为你挽回那份工作
I fought for your goddamn job.
我明白  我会永远心存感激
I know that, and I will always be grateful for it,
但实不相瞒
but I am telling you,
现在这样更好  因为...
it's better this way, because--
对谁更好  因为你不得不挣钱
Better for who? Based on that extra cash
向纳森上交罚金吗
that you had to throw at Nathan?
照我说这是为你自己好
I'd say it's better for you.
对每个人都好
For everybody.
我还是可以帮法律诊所处理案子
I can still have cases with the clinic.
我们还能一起工作
You and I can still work together.
我真幸运
Lucky me.
奥利佛  我回来的唯一原因是
Oliver, the only reason I went back
哈维承诺会做公益法律服务
is that Harvey committed to doing pro bonos, all right?
我处理的一半案子
Half of my cases,
和我在诊所时做的一样  只是这一次
the kind the clinic does, only this time,
我们有大律所的资源支持
with the resources of a big firm behind us.
是吗  那你现在手头是什么工作  迈克
Oh, really? What are you working on right now, Mike?
什么
What?
你回来后做的第一件事是什么
What's your first case back?
关于土地征用权还是侵犯公民权
Eminent domain? Civil rights violation?
奥利佛  别这样
Oliver, come on,
不是这样的  告诉我你回来的第一件事
It's not that-- - Tell me your first case back
如果不是为公司权贵端茶倒水
isn't carrying water for some corporate big shot,
我就马上闭嘴
and I'll shut my mouth right now.
玛莉莎说对了
Marissa was right.
你和我们共事只是为了等待时机
All you were doing with us was biding your time.
-这怎么回事  -你说什么
- What the fu-- is going on? - What do you mean?
案子结束了  你说过你会进行下一步
Case is over. You said you'd move.
我只是在推动进度
I'm just getting the ball rolling.
我如果没有自己的办公室无法处理案件
I can't work on my own cases if I don't have my own office.
听着  迈克
Listen, Mike.
你让那笔交易继续了
You let the goddamn sale go through.
-你不明白  -我不明白你说过
- You don't understand. - I understand that you said
你想在上位前和我最后一起做一个案子
that you wanted one last case together before you stepped up,
但你明显还未准备好要做领导
but you clearly are not ready to step up,
所以我得在这件律所消失之前
so I got to get my pro bono cases in
多花点时间处理我的公益案件
before this place doesn't even exist anymore.
你说完了吗  有空听我说说
Are you finished, or do you have a minute to hear
为什么我继续了交易吗
why I let the sale go through?
不  我不在乎
Oh, no, I don't care.
迈克  他知道我没有证据
Mike, I have no proof he knew.
他是杰西卡的委托人
He's Jessica's client.
如果他把我们再也无法处理他事务的事
How's it gonna look if he tells the world
公诸于众  会怎么样
that we can't handle his business anymore?
我现在告诉你会怎么样
Well, I'll tell you how it looks right now.
看起来你在害怕  而且说了不算
It looks like you're afraid and you're not in charge.
好吧  你要是这样跟我说话
Okay, you say something like that to me,
你最好做好挨揍的准备
you better get ready for a hit,
因为我一直在尽力而为
because I am doing the best I can.
不  哈维  你什么都没做
No, Harvey, you're not doing shit.
你在逃避  因为你害怕
You're hiding, 'cause you're afraid.
你害怕挑起这件律所的担子
You're afraid to take responsibility for this firm,
你也不会对自己承认这一点
and you won't admit it to yourself.
我不必听这些
I don't have to listen to this.
你必须听
Well, you're going to,
因为回想以前  你出于关心
'cause way back when, you cared enough about me
当着我的面说出了同样的话
to tell me the same thing to my face,
我现在只是在投桃报李
and I'm just returning the favor.
我不是她  迈克
I'm not her, Mike.
-我不是她  -你不必成为她
- I'm not her. - You don't have to be her.
你只用做回你自己
You just have to go back to being you.
我们第一次见面  聘用我的那个哈维
The Harvey I met the day you hired me,
他会走到尼尔・斯蒂尔曼面前
he would have gone in there and told Neil Stillman
告诉他去他妈的
to go fu-- himself.
所以由你决定
So it's up to you.
你可以继续躲在杰西卡阴影之下
You can keep hiding out in Jessica's shadow,
也可以走出阴影
or you get out of it
做一个霸道的哈维・斯佩克特
and start being Harvey goddamn Specter.
你也发现这里白天特别平静是吗
Do you find it peaceful here in the day too?
你带了我的支票过来
You're here to bring me my check,
那我的答案是肯定的
then the answer's yes.
我来这里告诉你我们终止了出售
I'm here to tell you that we stopped the sale.
你刚才说什么
What did you just say?
我们不参与你的骗局
We're not taking part in your fraud
所以你可以关掉你的烂公司了
so that you can dump your shitty company.
你这个混蛋  我不记得我给过你选项
You son of a bitch, I don't remember giving you a choice.
你给了  因为你的原话是
Well, you did, because your exact words were,
"要么同意  要么被解雇"
"Do it, or you're fired."
那你他妈被解雇了
Then you're goddamn fired.
你可以解雇我们  但一旦被解雇
You can let us go if you want, but the second you do,
我们会发一篇通讯稿声明
we're putting out a press release saying
皮尔逊-斯佩克特-利特不再代理
Pearson Specter Litt no longer represents clients
我们认为资产剥离中有不道德行为的委托人
we feel are unethical in their divestiture practices.
你不能这么做
You can't do that,
这触犯了律师-委托人的保密特权
that's attorney-client privilege.
不  因为我们不会对你指名点姓
No, it's not, because we're not gonna name you.
但你用屁股想都能猜到
But you can bet your ass the whole world
全世界都会知道我们说的是谁
is gonna know who we're talking about.
你想要什么
What do you want from me?
你是作为我的委托人在询问我吗
Are you asking me as my client?
因为我不提供免费法律建议
Because I don't give free legal advice.
是的  好吧  你还是我的律师
Yes, okay. You're still my attorney.
这样的话  接下来要做的是
In that case, here's what's gonna happen:
你去和你盗用配方的对象
you're gonna go into business
做一笔交易
with the guys whose process you stole.
你私下交给他们10%的公司股权
You're gonna quietly give them 10% of your company,
把商品售价提高两倍
you're gonna triple your price, and you're gonna have
两家公司就谁家的伏特加味道更好进行公开竞争
a very public feud over whose vodka tastes better.
然后在这相同产品的两大品牌间的战争中
And then we both profit from a war
我们均能从中获利
between two brands that have the exact same product.
达成双赢
Win-win.
或许你和杰西卡一样厉害
Maybe you are as good as Jessica.
或许是  或许不是
Maybe I am. Maybe I'm not.
但我和她的共识是
But the thing we have in common is
我们再也不会受任何委托人的摆布
we're never gonna be bullied by any of our clients.
好了  路易  我一直尽力做到通情达理
All right, Louis, I've tried to be reasonable,
但我不会再坐视不管
but I'm not gonna sit around and watch this anymore.
从现在起  你不再
As of this moment, you're no longer
-负责管理新律师  -这是你和谁的意思
- in charge of the associates. - Says you and what army?
抱歉  我没听懂
I'm sorry, I didn't catch that.
-我说你做不到  -不  我可以
- I said you can't do that. - Oh, yes, I can,
因为即使哈维明显还未告诉你
because even though Harvey clearly didn't tell you,
从昨晚开始  我成为了高级合伙人
as of last night, I'm a senior partner.
-你成为什么  -你没听错
- You're what? - That's right.
我给了哈维一张五十万美元的支票
I gave Harvey a check for half a million dollars.
我现在是高级合伙人  路易
I'm a partner now, Louis,
这意味着你那套
which means your whole
"你高高在上  我俯首称臣"的屁话
"You're up here and I'm down here" bullshit,
行不通了
not anymore.
合伙人
Partner?
你甚至都不是律师
You're not even a lawyer.
世界最顶尖的9家律所中  有4家的首席运营官
Neither are the Chief Operating Officers of four
也都不是律师
of the top nine firms in the world.
这简直是胡闹  我根本没同意
This is bullshit. I didn't agree to any of this.
我不管你同意还是不同意
I don't care whether you agreed to it or not.
你都得忍着
You're gonna live with it.
我也不管你的头衔是什么
And I don't give a shit what your supposed title is.
我是不会放手我的律师的
I'm not giving up my associates.
如果你觉得你可以就这样离开这间洗手间
And if you think you're gonna leave this bathroom
而不对我表示出我应得的尊重...
without giving me the respect I deserve--
我是不会放手我的律师的
I'm not giving up my associates.
够了
That's enough.
哈维  你这做的是什么狗屁决定
Harvey, what the hell kind of shit did you pull?
闭嘴听我说  路易
Shut up and listen, Louis.
唐娜要求在管理层有一席之位
Donna asked for a seat at the table,
而我同意了
and I gave her one,
因为先前为我工作时  她一直支持着我
because when she worked for me, she had my back,
愿意为我大杀四方
and would kill anyone coming for me,
而她先前为你工作时  一样尽心尽力
and when she worked for you, she did the same exact thing,
更别提如果她离开了
not to mention if she left tomorrow,
这家律所15分钟之内就会变为一滩散沙
this firm would be a pile of rubble within 15 minutes.
那就给她加薪啊
So then give her a raise.
但你不能就这样把她抬为高级合伙人
You don't make her goddamn senior partner.
假如杰西卡在  她也会和我做法一样的
If Jessica were here, she'd tell you to do the same exact thing.
但是  路易  杰西卡不在了
Well, Louis, Jessica isn't here,
但我在
but I am.
-谢谢你  哈维  -先别急着谢我
- Thank you, Harvey. - Don't thank me yet.
你要求大家投票表决  没问题
You asked for a vote. You got it.
但决定什么时候发起投票的人是我
But the person who's gonna decide when that vote is is me,
而我认为我们要做的第一件事
and I say our first order of business
是对外公布哈维・斯佩克特是新的管理合伙人
is putting out word that Harvey Specter is the new managing partner.
你们想对这个决定投票表决吗  来吧
Now, you want to vote on that? Let's do it.
但假如我们不能达成一致
But if it's not unanimous,
那就有大麻烦了
we're gonna have a big problem.
我没意见
No problem here.
你呢  路易
What about you, Louis?
你对我当老大有意见吗
You got a problem with me calling the shots?
没有  哈维
No, Harvey.
没意见  管理合伙人是你
No problem. You're managing partner.
很好  那我建议你们两个
Good. Then I suggest the two of you
在明天之前收拾好心情
get your shit together before tomorrow,
因为此时此刻  我还有事要忙
because right now, I've got some things to take care of.
我现在不想理你  路易...
I don't want to talk to you right now, Louis--
我想让你来接手那些律师
I want you to have the associates.
无论你对唐娜说了什么  你都没说错
Whatever you said to Donna, you were right.
-路易...  -瑞秋  让我说完
- Louis... - Rachel, just let me finish
趁着我还能说得出口
while I'm still able to get it out.
我知道我对他们是严厉了点...
I know I can be rough on them...
但那只是因为我希望看到他们
but it's only because I want to see them
成为他们能成为的最好的律师
become the best lawyers they can be.
但如今我不在最佳状态
But I'm not in the best headspace right now,
我如果一直把气撒在他们头上
and if I keep taking my anger out on them,
他们是无法成为伟大的律师的
they will not become great lawyers.
说不定他们都要直接退出法律界了  所以...
They might not stay in the law at all, so...
最好还是有别人暂时来接手一下
it's better that someone else takes over for a while,
而我想不到比你更合适的人选了
and I cannot think of a better person than you.
很抱歉我背着你行事了  路易
I'm sorry that I went behind your back, Louis.
你没做错
You were right to.
如果你当着我的面提出
If you had asked me face-to-face,
我都不知道我会做出什么
I don't even know what I would have done,
那种场景...光是想想都让我不舒服了
and that--just thinking about that makes me sick.
瑞秋  你就像是我的亲人
Rachel, you're family,
假如我连你都失去了...
and if I lose you too...
路易  你不会失去我的
Louis, you're not going to lose me,
但我觉得我知道你可能需要些什么
but I think I know what you may need.
你可千万别说是"假期"
Please don't say vacation.
如果再来一个人和我提玛莎葡萄园岛
If someone else mentions Martha's Vineyard one more time,
-我对天发誓...  -我想说的词是"终结"
- I swear to God... - I was gonna say closure.
假如你是想说我得去和塔拉谈谈...
If you're telling me that I need to talk to Tara--
路易  你本来都要结婚了
Louis, you were gonna get married.
你本来都要当父亲了
You were gonna be a father.
不能仅凭一通语音留言就结束这一切
That can't all end over a voicemail.
好好对他们
Treat them well.
我就知道
I knew it.
知道什么
Knew what?
你没种把哈维的旧办公室填满
You don't have the balls to fill Harvey's office.
好吧  唐娜  声明一下
Okay, Donna, just to be clear,
光看种可算不得男人
balls do not make the man.
-瑞秋可不是这么说的  -这话是什么意思
- That's not what Rachel says. - What does that even mean?
我觉得咱俩都明白这是什么意思
I think we both know what that means.
唐娜  和你声明一下
Donna, for the record,
我的"种"尺寸正常
my balls are within normal parameters.
所以你下来就是为了调侃我
So you just come down here to give me shit,
还是说有其他什么事情
or was there maybe another reason?
还能有什么事情
What other reason would I have?
我一个都想不出来
I can't think of a single one.
-那我来这里的任务就完成了  -很好
- Then my work here is done. - Good.
因为我显然不是下来告诉你
Because I certainly didn't come down here to tell you
我还记得你第一次进这间办公室的情景
I remember the first time you were in this office,
而我从没想到我会有
and I never thought I'd see the day
对你道喜的这一天  迈克
when I told you congratulations, Mike.
这一切都是你应得的
You deserve it as your own.
-谢谢你  唐娜  -不客气  迈克
- Thanks, Donna. - You're welcome, Mike.
你确定你不一起吗
Are you sure you don't come with it?
我是说  那边有张桌子
I mean, there is a desk right there
上面可是真真切切写着你的名字的
that literally has your name on it.
抱歉  我也希望我能来
Sorry, I wish I could,
但实际上我也分到了一间新办公室
but I actually got a new office too.
-真的吗  -必须得有一间
- You did? - Needed one,
因为等到明天
because as of tomorrow,
我就正式是这家律所最新一位高级合伙人了
I am officially the firm's newest senior partner.
我勒个去  你是认真的吗
Holy shit. Are you serious?
是的  而且从现在开始
Yes. And from now on,
你得说"您是认真的吗  女士"
it's, "are you serious, ma'am?"
-清楚了吗  小帅哥  -天啊
- Have you got that, pretty boy? - My God.
哈维造出了一个怪物是吧
Harvey's created a monster, hasn't he?
你无法想象
You have no idea.
唐娜...
Donna...
这也是你应得的
it's about time.
喂  我知道我们一直没谈过
Hey. I know we haven't spoken,
我们也没有好好地结束
and we didn't exactly leave things off well,
但是...
but...
我今天真的很需要见你一面
I just really need to see you tonight
假如还有一丝可能的话
if at all possible.
看来你终于做了投入了
Guess you got some skin in the game after all.
确实  格蕾琴
Sure did, Gretchen.
确实
Sure did.